Guide to the Barbara Howes Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal and Financial Papers, 1914-1995; Series III; 6.25; (7 boxes)
  - "The Poetry Center," pamphlet announcing reading by William Jay Smith and Barbara Howes on May 5, 1963 in New York, circa 1963 (Box 23)
  - "Auden's Library," booklet by Robert A. Wilson, signed "love from Bob" printed for Christmas, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Poster announcment for Barbara Howes' reading at Tufts University, March 9, 1960 (Box 23)
  - Brandeis University Creative Arts Grant, 1958 March 5 (Box 23)
  - Bennington Award, 1980 May (Box 23)
  - Financial records, undated; 2 (Box 23)
  - Hollins Critic, issue devoted to Howes, undated (Box 23)
  - Bennington College, Class of '37 50th Reunion Book, 1987 (Box 23)
  - Stark, Freya: tear sheet of article on Diana of Ephesus, undated (Box 23)
  - Rodman, Seden: copy of article on Haitian painting, undated (Box 23)
  - Hatian art reproductions, undated (Box 23)
    Reproductions of paintings for the Art Center of Port-au-Prince, Hiati (Obin; Duffaut; etc.)
  - Mailing lists, undated (Box 23)
  - Book list of Caribbean authors from University Place Bookshop, undated (Box 23)
  - Memorial to T. S. Eliot and Dame Edith Sitwell, program, 1965 (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous printed material, undated (Box 23)
  - "David's European Plans", undated (Box 23)
  - "Mrs. Parker Melodrama," research materials and correspondence regarding administrative crisis at Bennington College involving Gail T. Parker, circa 1975 (Box 23)
  - The Beaver Log, commencement book for Beaver Country Day School, 1931 (Box 23)
  - "Brazillian and African publications," research materials, undated (Box 23)
  - "Ronald Reagan," loose notes and clippings, undated (Box 23)
  - Financial records, 1980s (Box 23)
  - "Humane Society Business and Rows," business and organizational material, undated (Box 24)
  - "David's Italian Troubles," family documents regarding David Smith, early 1970s (Box 24)
  - "David's Austrian Troubles," family documents regarding David Smith, plus Howes' account, mid-1970s (Box 24)
  - "David - Important papers," family documents regarding David Smith, plus Howes' account, undated (Box 24)
  - "2nd Go-Round with Trapans - David," family documents regarding David Smith, 1973 (Box 24)
  - "David Innsbruck troubles / Austrian papers / Brunswick hospital papers," family documents regarding David Smith, 1975-1977 (Box 24)
  - "L. F. Rothschild," financial papers, late 1970s (Box 24)
  - "David and Greg," financial papers and letters regarding David and Gregory Jay Smith, undated (Box 24)
  - "MLPFS," financial papers and letters regarding Metropolitan Life transactions and statements, 1960s (Box 24)
  - "Medical Expenses and Insurance", 1960s-1970s (Box 24)
  - Tax records, 1976-1983; 4 (Box 24)
  - Royalty statements, 1961-1970 (Box 24)
  - Awards and certificates, 1975-1977 (Box 24)
    Copies of two awards received by Howes: The National Socrety of Literature and Arts (1975) and the National Register of Prominent Americans (1976-1977)
  - Printed material, undated; 2 (Box 24)
  - Unsorted material, undated (Box 24)
  - Royalty statements, 1971-1977 (Box 24)
  - "David and Gregory Jay Smith," notebooks about Barbara Howes' sons, undated (Box 24)
  - Passports, 1979, 1986 (Box 24)
  - "Southern Tenant Farmer's Union," pamphlets about sharecroppers, circa 1930s (Box 24)
  - "Indexed Genealogical Record," copy of record book of Howes' adoptive family, going back to 1703, including Robert Cook's last will and testament (1731), undated (Box 25)
  - Royalty statements and errata sheets, undated (Box 25)
  - Family documents, circa 1914-1920 (Box 25)
    Early notebook by Howes' mother describing the account of her arrival, early months with notations (to age 4), plus a list of books read to her during her first 6 years or so.
  - Notebook listing books read by Barbara Howes 1921-1930 (Box 25)
  - "Eranos," pamphlet, circa 1952 (Box 25)
  - "Important," notes about awards received by Howes, copyright, and notes from her "Form in Poetry" course, 1967 (Box 25)
  - "W.P.D." (Important), 1914-1965 (Box 25)
    One folder of six typewritten letters from Barbara Howes' birth father, William P. Dudley (1945-04); newspaper clippings about his suicide in 1965; two letters from Marika Dudley. Also included are Barbara Howes' adoption certificate (1914) and Baptism document (1928).
    Also included are a pamphlet, "The Mid Century in Exeter" about Exeter, NH; a newspaper clipping about the death of Albertus Dudley (1955) and a hand-written note which reads "corridors of life in him had narrowed down to a handful of obsessions."
  - Royalty Statements, 1978-1982 (Box 25)
  - Publicity, 1948-1980 (Box 25)
  - "About K.A.P.," newspaper clippings about Katherine Anne Porter, 1980-1981 (Box 25)
  - "About Eudora," newspaper clippings and autograph postcard from Eudora Welty, undated (Box 25)
  - "Prizes, lists, etc." newspaper clippings about literary prizes, undated (Box 25)
  - "B. Traven - articles, notes", undated (Box 25)
  - "NYC Medical Bills", 1987 (Box 25)
  - "Reunion 1987" reply to a 1986 Bennington College reunion questionnaire, 1986-1987 (Box 25)
  - "Anti-Reagan stuff," loose notes and articles about Ronald Reagan, undated (Box 25)
  - "Nature: Things of interest" loose notes and articles about nature, undated (Box 25)
  - "Things of interest: politics" One folder of misc. articles re: political issues, undated (Box 25)
  - "Things of interest: politics" One folder of misc. articles re: political issues, undated (Box 25)
  - "Things of Interest: People" One folder of misc. articles re: people like Malcolm Cowley, John Lennon, etc., undated (Box 25)
  - "National Book Award" Award, program and correspondence re: Barbara Howes' winning the 1995 National Book Award for Poetry ("Collected Poems") (Box 25)
  - "Guggenheim Fellowship" Framed award letter for a Barbara Howes' winning of a Guggenheim Fellowship for the years 1955-1956 (Box 25)
  - "National Institute of Arts and Letters", 1971 (Box 25)
    Framed award letter for a Barbara Howes' winning of an Award in Literature from the National Institute of Arts and Letters in 1971 (signed by William Maxwell).
  - Buxton 1973 Yearbook (Box 25)
  - Bookplates and lead type slug for Barbara Howes / William Jay Smith bookplate, undated (Box 25)
  - Reviews and clippings, undated (Box 26)
  - Scrapbook of articles about writers Howes knew, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 26)
  - Poster announcement of Barbara Howes' reading at Tufts University. March 9, 1960, plus copy of article in The Tufts Weekly (Box 26)
  - Dinesen, Isak: photograph for Harper's Bazaar, undated (Box 26)
- Photographs and Albums, 1916-1957; Series IV; 1.75; (5 boxes)
  Contains photographs and photo albums, particularly of Barbara Howes, her family, and some literary friends.
  - Photograph of Barbara Howes and William Jay Smith in Italy, 1950 April (Box 27)
  - Photograph of Barbara Howes and Richard Eberhart, undated (Box 27)
  - Framed photo of May Day Poetry Tournament, Second Church Boston awards, undated (Box 27)
  - Photograph Albums, 1947-1957; 3 (Box 27)
    Albums of black and white photographs taken of Barbara Howes and William Jay Smith and their sons while living in Italy, including shots of many literary figures.
    Photos include shots of writers such as W. H. Auden, Leonie Adams and William Troy, Dore Ashton, Enid Starkie, Caitlin Thomas, Stephen Spender, John McCiennan, Adja Yunkers, Jack Murphy, R.P. Blackmur, Thekla Clark, Newell Jenkins, Elizabeth Mann, Jane Sabersky, etc.
  - Photographs, including early photographs of Italy and Howes' real mother and father, undated; 6 (Box 27)
  - Photographs of Italy and Pownal, Vermont in early stages of Brook House, 1940s; 4 (Box 27)
  - F.lli Alinari photographs of Italian art, 1940s (Box 27)
  - Snapshots of William Jay Smith and Stephen Spender, Eudora Welty, Richard Wilbur and Louis Untermeyer, undated (Box 27)
  - Photograph of W. H. Auden, C. Day Lewis and Stephen Spender, by Natasha Spender, circa 1950 (Box 27)
  - Photograph of Barbara Howes and her grandmother, undated (Box 27)
  - Framed diptych of two photos of Barbara Howes' mother, taken when she was a child and later, in old age, undated (Box 27)
  - Photo albums of family in Montana and Petersham, New Hampshire, undated (Box 28)
  - Photo albums of family in Montana and Petersham, New Hampshire, undated (Box 29)
  - Photo album of family in Montana and Petersham, New Hampshire, undated (Box 30)
  - Photograph of Barbara Howes as a child, circa 1916 (Box 31)
  - Photograph of Mildred Howes, Barbara Howes and Priscilla, 1918 (Box 31)
  - Photograph album, undated (Box 31)
    Album with photographs of Newell Jenkins; Georgia and Mildred; Howes, William Jay Smith and David on Vulcania May 1957; Pownal, Vermont; Florence, Italy (of various "Triumphs" and "Statue of Chimera" that inspired Howes' poetry).
- 1960-1966 Gifts of Barbara Howes Writings, 1959-1965; 0.42; (1 box)
  Arranged in alphabetical order by title.
  Drafts of eight poems, three novels, and a script for a Voice of America program.
  - Adam and Noble, 1965? (Box 32)
  - "The Cardinal", undated (Box 32)
  - Cold Wave, undated; 2 (Box 32)
  - "The Dressmaker's Dummy at Scarecrow", undated (Box 32)
  - "For an Old Friend", undated (Box 32)
  - "For K.A.P.", 1965 May 5 (Box 32)
  - "The Lace Maker", undated (Box 32)
  - "Leaning Into Light", undated (Box 32)
  - Light and Dark, 1959 (Box 32)
  - "The Lonely Pipefish", undated (Box 32)
  - A Private Signal, undated; 3 (Box 32)
  - "A View of Poetry", undated (Box 32)
- Restricted Fragile Material, 0.25; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Contact Access Services for further information.
  - Barbara Howes reading, undated; 1; 00:57:26 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002109974353)
    Box 33 (audiotape reel): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.